what's up everybody Phil Blackman with
barbend.com the 2023 CrossFit Games in
Madison Wisconsin have come to a close
and we have our Champions Laura Horvath
and Jeffrey Adler are the fittest on
Earth we're gonna break down their
performance throughout the entire
competition week but before we do that
hit that subscribe button if you want to
catch any of barban's coverage of the
games or any strength sport in general
whether it's bodybuilding powerlifting
weightlifting strongman or of course
CrossFit bar Bend has you covered for
the first time in seven years a woman
other than Tia Claire to me sits Atop
The Throne as CrossFit Games Champion
Laura Horvath is the fittest woman on
earth it is her sixth career appearance
at the game she had previously finished
on the podium on three separate
occasions finishing second in 2018 and
2021 and third in 2022 and now she
Reigns Supreme in 2023. she had a
remarkably consistent performance
throughout the 2023 games with four
events wins and only finished outside
the top 15 a single time she ranked in
the top 10 in 9 out of 12 events
including the final event in which she
wore the leader's Jersey here's a
breakdown of her full performance across
all 12 events Horvath opened her 2023
CrossFit Games campaign with a top 10
finish in event one she built upon that
with a first place finish in event 2
that featured two heavy Pig flips that
played to her advantage over the rest of
the game's field her strength the
strength-based workway events are where
Horvath usually shines gymnastics seem
to be her only noticeable weakness on
the competition floor as represented by
her 27th Place finish in event 3 the
inverted medley fortunately for Horvath
the rest of the programming played to
her strength she bounced back
immediately with a runner-up finishing
event four and a second event win in the
games in event five after a mid-pack
finish in event six corvath was towards
the top of the overall leaderboard but
needed big finishes on the weekend if
she was going to claim the title of
Fitness on Earth and that's exactly what
she did she kicked off Saturday with a
13th Place finish in the 5K to maintain
her spot toward the top of the
leaderboard she proceeded to slide up
the ranks with an eighth place finish in
intervals to get her sights on the
leader at the time Emma Lawson of Canada
the night closed with Horvath scoring
the heaviest Olympic total of any woman
on the floor of 470 pounds the final day
of the CrossFit Games was horvath's day
she opened with back-to-back wins in
events 10 and 11 to assume the overall
lead on the leaderboard by 22 points she
entered the final event wearing the
leaders jersey and only needed to stay
within two ranks of Emma Lawson in the
final event to take the crown ultimately
she finished in fourth in the final
event to leave as the CrossFit Games
Champion moving over to the men's
division Jeffrey Adler of Canada is the
fittest man on Earth the 2023 CrossFit
Games represented Adler's fifth career
appearance at crossfit's grandest stage
he had previously finished in the top
five twice fifth in 2020 and then again
in 2022. let's take a look at Jeffrey
Adler's entire performance at the 2023
CrossFit Games Adler scored two first
place event finishes his first coming in
event six Helena and his second in event
10 the muscle up logs Adler kicked off
his games with a runner-up finish to
yanukowski in event one however after a
poor performance in event 2 and a
middling performance in event 3 it
seemed as though the top of the
leaderboard was going to be Out Of Reach
however however the games are a marathon
not a Sprint it was during day two of
individual competition that Adler would
Mount his comeback he scored back to
back eighth place finishes in events
four and five followed by his first win
in event six entering the weekend it
seemed as though it would be a two-horse
race between Jeffrey Arthur and Roman
karenikov who had led the men's division
for the majority of the games up until
that point ather who's most known for
his raw strength showed how he had
markedly improved his running during his
training as illustrated by his second
place finish in the cross-country 5K
Adler stayed towards the top of the
field during Saturday's remaining events
he ranked seventh in event 8 and 4th in
event nine aiding Adler's rise to the
top was karenikov having his worst day
of the competition ranking 16th and 17th
in events 8 and 9th respectively on
Saturday night Adler kicked off the
final day of competition with his second
win of the games in event 10.
unfortunately in that same event
krenikov suffered a foot injury due to
an awkward Landing over one of the logs
in the penultimate event karenikov
limped down to the Coliseum floor
knowing that he could not apply pressure
to his left foot he performed the double
unders and sled on one leg as a result
of getting capped in the workout and add
the ranking seventh in the event Adler
took the overall lead at the wore the
leader's Jersey into the final event of
competition and was effectively
mathematically locked for the title a
tremendous comeback mixed with
remarkable consistency and noticeable
improvements from his 2022 capabilities
from day two onward resulted in either
winning his first ever CrossFit Games
title so there you have it Laura Horvath
Jeffrey Adler are the fittest on Earth
I'm Phil Blackman for barbend.com thanks
for watching